Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Trust Inventory of Getty Publications, 1954-2013 and undated IA10020
Institutional Records and Archives
- Getty Center for Education in the Arts (GCEA), 1984-1999; undated; Series VI.
  During its first ten years, the Getty Center for Education in the Arts / GEI concentrated on the implementation and dissemination of DBAE. This was achieved by advocating for the value of arts in education, through the dissemination of print publications and videotapes, national conferences, and collaborative projects; professional development for school and university personnel, through in-service programs such as the Los Angeles Institute; theory development to encourage evolution of DBAE, through seminars, doctoral fellowships, and the commissioning of scholarly publications; curriculum development to support creation of model instructional materials; and special initiatives to encourage others to champion DBAE. In January 1986 responsibility for administering arts education grants was transferred from the Trust's Grant Program to the Center for Education in the Arts. The goal of the arts education grant program was to support the development of model DBAE programs across the country. In addition to improving the quality of arts education in primary and secondary schools, the GEI also concentrated on the education of museum visitors. Focus group research and other studies resulted in a number of publications aimed at the museum community.
  Material comprises Getty publications produced by or about the Getty Center for Education in the Arts and its activities.
  - Fowler, Charles B., ed. Arts in Education, Education in Arts: Entering the Dialogue of the 80's. 1984. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Beyond Creating: The Place for Art in America's Schools. Los Angeles: 1985. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Eisner, Elliot W. The Uncertain Profession: Observations on the State of Museum Education in Twenty American Art Museums. 1986. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Discipline-Based Art Education - What Forms will it Take?: Proceedings of a National Invitational Conference, Los Angeles, California, January 15-17, 1987. Los Angeles: 1987. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Broudy, Harry S. The Role of Imagery in Learning. Los Angeles: 1987. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Eisner, Elliot W. The Role of Discipline-Based Art Education in America's Schools. Los Angeles: [1987]. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Eisner, Elliot W. The Role of Discipline-Based Art Education in America's Schools. Los Angeles: [1987]., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Issues in Discipline-Based Art Education: Strengthening the Stance, Extending the Horizons. A National Invitational Seminar Sponsored by the Getty Center for Education in the Arts, Cincinnati, Ohio May 21-24, 1987. Los Angeles: 1988., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - The Preservice Challenge: Discipline-Based Art Education and Recent Reports on Higher Education. A National Invitational Seminar Sponsored by the Getty Center for Education in the Arts, Snowbird, Utah, August 8-15, 1987. Century City: 1988., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Roundtable Series II: Proceedings Report. Los Angeles: 1988 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Arnheim, Rudolf. Thoughts on Art Education. Los Angeles: 1989. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Education in Art: Future Building: Proceedings of a National Invitational Conference February 2-4, 1989. Los Angeles: 1989. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Liberal Education, Volume 75, No. 2 March/April 1989. Association of American Colleges, Washington, DC: 1989. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Dobbs, Stephen. M. Learning in and Through Art. 1989., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Proceedings: Education in Art - Future Building. 1989. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Arts for Life (Video). Los Angeles: 1990. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Be Smart Include Art: A Planning Kit for PTAs. 1990. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Gardner, H. Art Education and Human Development. Los Angeles: 1990. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Kaagan, Stephen S. Aesthetic Persuasion: Pressing the Cause of Arts Education in American Schools. Los Angeles: 1990. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Leach, Nicky, ed. From Snowbird I to Snowbird II: Final Report on the Getty Center Preservice Education Project. Los Angeles: 1990. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Seminar Proceedings: Inheriting the Theory - New Voices and Multiple Perspectives on DBAE, May 4-7, 1989 (Austin, Texas) Los Angeles: 1990. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Alexander, Kay, and Michael Day. Discipline-Based Art Education: A Curriculum Sampler. (loose-leaf binder and contents) Los Angeles: 1991. (Box 2012.IA.01-22)
  - Future Tense: Arts Education Technology, January 24-26, 1991 An Invitational Conference. 1991. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Future Tense: Arts Education Technology: Conference Summary, January 24-26, 1991. Los Angeles: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - Insights: Museums, Visitors, Attitudes, Expectations. Los Angeles: 1991., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Insights: Museums, Visitors, Attitudes, Expectations (Video). Los Angeles: 1991. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Dobbs, Stephen. M. DBAE Handbook: An Overview of Discipline-Based Art Education. 1992. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Loyacono, Laura L. Reinventing the Wheel: A Design for Student Achievement in the 21st Century. National Conference of State Legislatures, Denver: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - More than Pumpkins in October: Visual Literacy in the 21st Century. Alexandria, VA: 1992., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Arts Education Principles/Standards: An ICFAD Position. International Council of Fine Arts Deans, San Marcos, TX: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - Birault, Monique M. Demographics of the Art Museum Profession: An Annotated Bibliography. 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - Seminar Proceedings: Discipline-based Art Education and Cultural Diversity, August 6-9, 1992, Austin, Texas. Santa Monica: 1993, (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Improving Visual Arts Education: Final Report on the Los Angeles Getty Institute for Educators on the Visual Arts (1982-1989). Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Perspectives on Education Reform: Arts Education as Catalyst. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - The Power of the Arts to Transform Education: An Agenda for Action. 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - Discipline-Based Music Education: A Conceptual Framework for the Teaching of Music, A Report of the Proceedings of an Invitational Conference on Discipline-Based Music Education, August 1994. 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - National Standards for Arts Education. Music Educators National Conference. Reston, VA: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Perkins, David N. The Intelligent Eye: Learning to Think by Looking at Art. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - The Vision for Arts Education in the 21st Century: The Ideas and Ideals Behind the Development of the National Standards for Education in the Arts. Music Educators National Conference, Reston, VA: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
  - Boston, Bruce O. Connections: The Arts and the Integration of the High School Curriculum. The College Board and the Getty Center for the Education in the Arts. New York: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Chalmers, F.G. Celebrating Pluralism: Art, Education, and Cultural Diversity. Los Angeles: 1996. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Educating for the Workplace through the Arts: Conference to be held Jan. 9-10, 1997 at the Getty Center, Los Angeles, CA. Los Angeles: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Educating for the Workplace through the Arts: Conference to be held Jan. 9-10, 1997 at the Getty Center, Los Angeles, CA. Los Angeles: 1996. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Arts Education for Life and Work. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Arts Education for Life and Work. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Arts Work: A Call for Arts Education for all California Students. California Department of Education, Sacramento: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Using ArtsEdNet: Opening Doors to Arts Education from the Getty Education Institution for the Arts. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Wilson, Brent. The Quiet Evolution: Changing the Face of Arts Education. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Wilson, Brent. The Quiet Evolution: Changing the Face of Arts Education: Executive Summary. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Wilson, Brent. The Quiet Evolution: Changing the Face of Arts Education. Executive Summary. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Anderson, Stephen S., Claudia Flanders and David Landers. Trajan's Rome: The Man, the City, the Empire, A Unit of Study for Grades 6-9. Los Angeles: 1998., (2 copies) (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Information, Getty Education Institution for the Arts. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Information, Getty Education Institution for the Arts. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Publications, Getty Education Institute for the Arts. Los Angeles 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Robinson, Ken. Facing the Future: The Arts and Education in Hong Kong, Report on the Arts and Education in Hong Kong: An International Symposium March 1997. Hong Kong Arts Development Council, Hong Kong: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Task Force on Children's Learning and the Arts: Birth to Age Eight. Young Children and the Arts: Making Creative Connections. Arts Education Partnership, Washington, DC: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - All Our Futures: Creativity, Culture & Education. Department for Education and Employment, Sudbury, Suffolk: 1999. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Fiske, Edward B., ed. Champions of Change: The Impact of the Arts on Learning. The Arts Education Partnership and the President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities, Washington, DC: [1999]. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Gaining the Arts Advantage: Lessons From School Districts that Value Arts Education. President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities and Arts Education Partnership, Washington, DC: 1999. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - A Guide to Arts and Education Collaboration, Learning Partnerships: Improving Learning in Schools with Arts Partners in the Community. Arts Education Partnership, Washington DC: 1999. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - International Conference on the Future of Arts Education, Global Perspectives for the New Millennium, New York, November 11-13, 1999. The New York International Festival of Arts, New York: 1999. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Proceedings Report: Beyond Creating Roundtable Series. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 16)
  - Transforming Education Through the Arts Challenge, Final Project Report Executive Summary. The National Arts Education Consortium, Columbus, OH: [2003]. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Transforming Education Through the Arts Challenge, Final Project Report. The National Arts Education Consortium, Columbus, OH: [2003]. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
- Other, 1997; 1998,; 2001; Series VII.
  - Silverman, Ron. Testing the In-Service Hypothesis: The Getty's Los Angeles DBAE Institute. Found in Visual Arts Research, Fall 1997 Vol. 23, No. 2. Champaign, IL: 1997. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
    Published by University of Illinois Press (non-Getty publication).
  - Hirsch, Jeffrey, text. Seeing the Getty Center: Buildings & Gardens. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-36)
    2-volume set: Seeing the Getty Center; Seeing the Getty Gardens. Packaged as box set.
  - Burlingham, Cynthia, and Bruce Whiteman, eds. The World From Here: Treasures of the Great Libraries of Los Angeles. Los Angeles: 2001. (Box 2012.IA.01-10)